# Shinji Pons, Senior Product Designer

Toulouse, France +33 07 44 74 31 34 hello@shinjipons.com

Links	Portfolio Linkedin					
Summary	•	I'm a results-driven product designer with 10 years of experience designing complex desktop software applications for creative professionals in the automotive, video game and animation industries.				
Areas of Expertise	Product Design	Figma	Python			
	UI/UX Design	Blender	JavaScript			
	Wireframing	Autodesk Alias	HTML/CSS			
	Prototyping	3D Modelling				

### **Employment History**

Jun 2023 - May 2024

## Senior Product Designer at Ragdoll Dynamics

Toulouse, France

Sole designer at an early-stage company revolutionizing 3D character animation through rigid body simulation. Key contributions include:

- Designing a new standalone desktop application and creating a comprehensive design system from the ground up.
- · Contributing to the testing and release of the Ragdoll Dynamics for Blender add-on.
- · Prototyping interface elements using ImGui integrated via JavaScript.
- Improving customer processes by adopting Attio, enhancing communication and customer relationship management.

Jan 2021 - May 2023

## Senior Experience Designer at Electronic Arts

Guildford, United Kingdom

Worked on Frostbite, EA's proprietary game engine, enhancing tools and workflows for over 5000 professionals across EA's studios. Key achievements include:

- Shaping future character creation workflows for key AAA titles such as Skate, EA FC, and UFC.
- Focusing on character workflows for EA Sports & Racing titles, including runtime deformation and mass loading of character assets.

May 2019 - Dec 2021

### Senior Product Designer at The LEGO Group

Billund, Denmark

Modernized LEGO Digital Designer Pro, the in-house 3D CAD-like modeller. Contributions include:

- Leading the design experience by leveraging brick data for improved connectivity, pricing, and collision detection.
- Reducing repetitive task time by up to 90% through redesigning essential tools.
- · Building a fully digital pipeline from concept to marketing for 70% of new LEGO products.

Employment History (cont	inued)			
Jun 2017 - May 2019	Experience Designer at Autodesk		Hanover, Germany	
	<ul> <li>Directed design for fast concept modelling and computational design in Alias, the leading 3D CAD software. Achievements include:</li> <li>Leading the design of subdivision modelling features in Alias 2020.</li> <li>Conducting user testing workshops with over 60 professional users from top automotive studios like Volvo and Toyota.</li> <li>Delivering tools that sped up concept design finalization by 60%.</li> </ul>			
Apr 2016 - Apr 2017	Experience Designer at Thomson Reuters		London, United Kingdom	
	Designed prototypes and features using natural language processing to automate risk detection in the World-Check Risk Intelligence product.			
Feb 2015 - Nov 2015	User Experience Designer at Microsoft		London, United Kingdom	
	Created interactive experiences in public spaces to raise awareness of the Windows Devices brand.			
Dec 2014 - Feb 2015	User Interface Designer at Style.com		London, United Kingdom	
	Designed branding and user interface elements for a fashion, travel, and luxury content and e-commerce platform.			
Education				
2010 - 2014	London Coll	London, United Kingdom		
	Bachelor of Arts, Graphic & Media Design (First Class Honours)			
Languages	French	Native speaker		
	English	Native speaker		
Internships				
Sep 2014 - Dec 2014	Graphic Design Intern at Barnbrook London, United Kingdo			
	Designed, laid out, and art-worked for clients including Art Basel and David Bowie.			

Graphic Design Intern at Ateliers Jean Nouvel

English, and Arabic).

Designed icon and typographic signage systems for the Louvre Abu Dhabi (in French,

Paris, France

Oct 2012 - Jan 2013